准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
美人鱼战士
和企鹅男孩
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
客串
配音  美人鱼战士
配音  企鹅男孩
蟹堡王
啊  蟹堡王
Ah, the Krusty Krab
走进过这扇大门的有不少海底生物
Through these doors
pass all the many kinds of undersea life
走进大门
Through the double doors
出发
Away
以及这两位
Also these guys
都跟你说了我不饿  美人鱼战士
I told you I'm not hungry, Mermaidman
胡说八道  企鹅男孩
Nonsense, Barnacleboy
一定要强身健体
We've got to keep up our strength
才有力气对抗邪恶
for the fight against evil
太破烂了
What a dive
前往收银台
To the register
出发
Away
你们要什么
Can I help you?
我要来个双层蟹黄堡和珊瑚块
A double Krabby Patty and coral bits for me
给小的来个笨笨套餐
and a Silly Meal for the lad
我不是想要玩具  只是
It's not for the toy, I just, uh
要保持身材穿紧身衣  懂吗
I gotta fit in the tights, you know?
随便你们
Whatever
请付五块钱
Five dollars, please
没问题  小伙子
You got it, Bucky
这么多够吗
Will this cover it?
不够
No
听好了  大鼻子
Listen, Big Nose
那人自从你出生之前就在救你命了
That guy's been saving your butt
since before you were born
传奇人物就没个优惠什么的吗
Don't you got a Living Legend discount or something?
这是家饭店  不是图书馆
This is a restaurant, not a lending library
而且你管谁叫大鼻子  大鼻子
And who're you calling Big Nose, Big Nose?
等下次危机到来
The next time danger threatens
就别指望我们会救你
don't expect any help from us
怕死我了
I'm shaking
还美人鱼战士企鹅男孩呢
Mermaidman and Barnacleboy
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩
一定
Must
要
get
签名
autograph
要想长得跟我一样壮
If you want to grow up strong like me
得留个几秒腾出空间
you gotta make room for seconds
服务生来了
Here comes our waiter
签
Auto
名
graph
我的天啊  是那个海绵小子
Holy sea cow, it's that sponge kid
动作快
Quick lad
前往无影船
To the invisible boat mobile
出发
Away
船停哪来着
Where'd we park?
能找你们签名吗
Can I have your autograph?
能找你们
Can I have your?
他们走了
They're gone
美人鱼战士的腰带
Mermaidman's belt
等等
Wait
用无影船钥匙警报就能找到了
We'll find it with the invisible boat alarm
船在那
There she is
早跟你说得开自动挡的
I told you we should've got the automatic
先别走
Hey guys, wait up
我有东西要给你们
I've got something for you
油门踩到底
Floor it
你们忘拿腰带了
You forgot your belt
你们忘
You forgot
美人鱼战士的秘密多用途腰带
Mermaidman's secret utility belt
海底正义的象征
The emblem of submersible justice
六十五年来  这个腰带协助防止了
For 65 years, this belt has helped prevent
各国的覆灭
the fall of nations
还有走光
And pants
它居然到了我的手上
I can't believe I'm actually holding it in my hands
我应该得还回去
Well, I guess I should return it
才怪
Or not
上班期间我可以好好保管
I could just hold on to it until after work
跟美人鱼战士的腰带独处
All alone with Mermaidman's belt
不知道这按钮干什么的
I wonder what this button does
缩小射线
The small ray
你的奶昔  先生
Here's your shake, sir
拿去吧
There you go
欢迎下次再来  先生
Come again, sir
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
里面是怎么回事
What's going on in here?
怎么东西全变小了
Why is everything all tiny?
我不知道
I don't know
你身上什么东西
What have you got?
没有
Nothing
不  真的
No, really
没有
Nothing
你肯定藏了东西
You've got something all right
给我看
Let's see it
不行
No, no
那是美人鱼战士的腰带吗
Is that Mermaidman's belt?
对
Yes
不敢相信他居然会借给你
I can't believe he'd lend it to you
我
Me, uh
也不信
either
这玩意应该不是他借你的吧
He didn't lend it to you, did he?
拜托别告状
Please don't tell
是你偷的
You stole it
拜托别告状
Please don't tell
我要告状了
I'm telling
章鱼哥  让美人鱼战士发现
Squidward, If Mermaidman finds out
肯定会把我踢出粉丝俱乐部
he'll kick me out of his fan club for sure
拜托别告状
Please don't tell
有电话
There's the phone
别
Don't
我在朝着电话走过去
I'm walking towards the phone
不要
No
我离电话越来越近了
I'm getting closer to the phone
别
Don't
现在是万众期待的时刻
And now for the moment we've all been waiting for
我求你了
I'm begging you
喂
Hello
我想找美
I'd like to speak to Mer
怎么
What did
喂
Hello?
你把我怎么了
What did you do to me?
对不起  都是你逼我的
I'm sorry, but you made me do it
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
要是不马上把我恢复成正常大小
if you don't return me to normal size right now
那你就真的要惹上大麻烦了
you are going to be in really big trouble
好吧
Okay
我说马上
I said now
听见了没
Do you hear me?
什么鬼东西
Holy fish paste
弄下去
Get it off me
你是不会用那东西吗
Don't you know how to work that thing?
我会的
I can do it
住手
Stop
我有个办法
I've got an idea
打电话找美人鱼战士
Let's call Mermaidman and
不行
No
不能让你这么做
I can't let you do that
肯定有谁可以帮的上忙
But there must be someone else who can help
聪明有智慧
Someone smart and wise
还有多年的阅历
with years of life experience
派大星
Patrick
派大星  派大星
Patrick, Patrick
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
派大星  我刚在上班
Patrick, I was at work
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩来了
and Mermaidman and Barnacleboy came
我就有了这腰带  然后你看
and I got this belt and look
章鱼哥手办
A Squidward action figure
让我玩他
Let me play with him
不行  派大星
No, Patrick
战斗机飞行员
Fighter pilot
轰炸
Dive bomb
派大星
Patrick
然后吃我一拳
And then comes a giant fist
派大星  不要
Patrick, no
那不是手办
That's not an action figure
是真的章鱼哥
that's the real Squidward
我不小心缩小他了
I shrunk him by accident
那也吃我一拳
And then comes a giant
等等  你不明白
Wait, you don't understand
事情很严重
This is serious
我不知道怎么办才能放大回去
I don't know how to un-shrink him
可能他后半辈子都只能这么小了
He could be stuck like this for the rest of his life
别想太多了
Don't worry about it
他总有一天会找到真爱
He'll find love one day
真的吗
You think so?
没错  不过对象得跟他差不多大
Sure, but it'll be with someone his own size
比如这个腌椰菜
Like this pickle
看吧
See?
他们相亲相爱
They like each other
不行
No
要是我会用这东西就好了
If only I knew how to work this thing
给我看一下
Let me take a look at it
知道问题出在哪吗
You know what the problem is?
哪
What?
你把它设置成了M  表示小
You got it set to "M", for mini
应该得设置成W  表示巨
When it should be set to "W", for "wumbo"
派大星  巨好像有些意义不明
Patrick, I don't think "wumbo" is a real word
得了吧
Come on
你也知道
You know
我巨  你巨
I wumbo, you wumbo
他她我巨
he-she-me wumbo
动词原型巨  现在分词巨
Wumbo, wumboing
不知道从这么高的地方摔下去
I wonder if a fall from this height
会不会摔死我
would be enough to kill me
巨学
Wumbology?
巨研究
The study of wumbo?
连一年级小朋友都会  海绵宝宝
It's first grade, SpongeBob
派大星  真对不起我先前质疑你
Patrick, I'm sorry I doubted you
那就好
Well, all right, then
开始吧
Let 'er rip
成功了
It worked
不好了
Oh, no
快看
Look
海绵宝宝变大了
SpongeBob's giant
等下我能不能变大
Can I be giant next?
派大星  不是我变大了
Patrick, I'm not giant
是你也变小了
You've shrunk, too
开什么玩笑
You're kidding
还好我还有这个腌椰菜
Good thing I've still got this pickle
现在你还会带我们去找美人鱼战士吗
Now will you take us to Mermaidman?
不行
No
不能让他发现
He can never find out
不过我会想办法的
But I'll think of something
我保证
I promise
期间你们就安全待在这个罐子里
Until then, you'll be safe in this jar
知道还有什么很好笑吗
You know what's funny?
我腌椰菜一开始出了个罐子
My pickle started out in a jar
现在又进了个罐子
and now it's in one again
就好像双关笑话什么的
It's like a pun or something
It's only two people
才缩小了俩
没什么大不了
No big deal
不会有别的目击者了
Nobody else saw it
你好  海绵宝宝
Howdy, SpongeBob
珊迪
Sandy
你怎么
What did you
岂有
For cryin'
你把我怎么了
What did ya'll do to me?
对不起  珊迪
I'm sorry, Sandy
美人鱼战士进来就
Mermaidman came in, and
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
Hey, SpongeBob?
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
你好  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
海绵兄
Sponge-Dude
裤头村
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  嗨
SpongeBob, hi
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
你好啊  海绵哥
What's up, Sponge
我得找个更大的罐子了
I'm gonna have to get a bigger jar
海绵宝宝  能不能别自己骗自己了
SpongeBob, will you just face facts?
你已经把裤头村全体居民都缩小了
You've shrunken everybody in Bikini Bottom
必须去找美人鱼战士
You've got to go to Mermaidman
章鱼哥  他一定会失望的
Squidward, he'll be so disappointed
你不能害我们永远都这么小
Well, you can't leave us small forever
你们不理解
You don't understand
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你要承认你的错误
You need to admit your mistake
妈
Mom?
你妈说得对  孩子
Your mother's right, son
美人鱼战士会理解的
Mermaidman will understand
你就是美人鱼战士  老不死的
You're Mermaidman, you old coot
啊对
Oh, yeah
美人鱼战士
Mermaidman?
真对不起
I'm so sorry
我只是你的头号粉丝
It's just that I'm such a big fan
然后你的腰带
and your belt
不用怕  孩子
Don't worry, son
我能理解
I understand
回想起我第一次用腰带的时候
Why, I remember back when I first used the belt
那是一九零一一还是一二来着
the year was nineteen, aught, eleventy-twelve
那时候的总统应该是
Why, I believe the president then was
告诉他要怎么把我们放大回去
Just tell him how to un-shrink us
啊对  放大射线
Oh, yes, the un-shrink ray
我想想
Let's see, uh
你设置成巨了没
Did you set it to wumbo?
什么
What?
抓住海绵宝宝
Get SpongeBob
现在我得开五英里的船
Now I have to drive five miles
才能去上卫生间
to go to the bathroom
还是在我自己家
In my own home
爬一级台阶我都得坐电梯
And I need an elevator to climb one stair
我们都缩小好多年了
We've been shrinking for years
可这也太离谱了
But this is ridiculous
所有东西都太大了
Everything's too big
有了
I've got it
哒哒
Ta-da
既然我没法放大你们
Since I couldn't make you big
那我就缩小城市
I made the city small
现在只要再缩小一样东西
And now only one more thing to shrink
茄子
Cheese
感觉还行
I guess this is okay
对啊  也没多大区别
Yeah, what's the difference?
好办法  海绵宝宝
Good idea, SpongeBob
回家的感觉真好
Well, it's great to be back
坐牢记
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
你放心  泡芙老师
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff
滑浪学校
就是这个
this is the one
海绵宝宝  快想啊
SpongeBob, think, think
往那边转  往那边转
Turn that way, turn that way
不对  往那边转
No, turn that way
右转  左转
Right, left
上转  下转
Up, down
不行
No
真是的  不能那么做
Come on, don't ever do that
加把劲
Come on
不
No
我准备好了
I'm ready
我能行的  泡芙老师
I can do this, Mrs. Puff
我能行的  我能行的
I can do it, I can do it
驾考结束了  海绵宝宝
The driving test is over, SpongeBob
停船
Stop the boat
等等
Wait
我能行的  泡芙老师
I can do this, Mrs. Puff
我能行的
I can do this
回马路  海绵宝宝
The road, SpongeBob
快回马路上
Get back on the road
一定要考过
Got to pass the test
一定要过
Got to pass
西瓜怎么你了
What do you got against the melons?
小心
Look out
这一定是驾考的夜路部分
This must be the night-driving part of the test
我们要让你端正做好自己
We're going to straighten you out
用这个修理你
This'll fix you
继续修那个
Now let's get that one
真见鬼
Barnacles
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
看到了
Yeah
那位前面没挂车牌
That guy had no front license plate
抓住他
Let's get him
快看那些警察
Look at all those police
不知道是不是总统来了
I wonder if the president's in town
小心
Look out
我满怀无比自豪的心情
It is with great pride
正式启用这座未完工的大桥
that I officially open this unfinished bridge
我哪里出错了
Where did I go wrong?
滑浪学校
我开设了一所新滑浪学校
With the opening of my new boating school
特此庄严承诺只要有学生愿意学
I pledge that as long as a student is willing to learn
就绝不放弃他
I shall never give up
嗨  我是海绵宝宝
Hi, I'm SpongeBob SquarePants
荫凉滩疗养院
赶紧卸下这一整车的水果潘趣酒
Hurry up with that truckload of fruit punch
老人家都快发癫了
The seniors are getting cranky
活着
Alive
我还活着
I'm alive
感谢海神王  我还
Thank Neptune, I'm still
各位老人家  大家开窗
All right, seniors, let's open these windows
让全世界看见你们洁白的衣装
so the world can see your nice white clothes
好一个适合冲浪
It's gonna be a surfin'
冲浪
Surfin'
冲浪的夏天  好一个
Surfin' summer, it's gonna
终于写好了
It's finally finished
我白纸红字写的生平回忆录
A memoir of my life, written in red ink
真见鬼
Oh, barnacles
海绵宝宝  你没事吧
SpongeBob, are you okay?
看情况
That depends
我考过了吗
Did I pass?
不许动
Freeze
你被捕了
You're under arrest
慢着
Hold it
不能逮捕他
You can't arrest him
他只是个驾校学员
He's just a student driver
我们说的不是他
We're not talking about him
可我不属于这里
But I don't belong here
这都是个天大的误会
It's all a big mistake
对  我也不属于这里
Yeah, I don't belong here, either
我也是
Me, too
我是无辜的
I'm innocent
我属于这里
I belong here
好
Okay
你能行的  泡芙
you can do this, Puff
你能保持理智熬过去的
You can get through this without losing your sanity
可不能再走上老路
That's a road we don't want to go down again
好处
Positives
想想好处
Think of the positives
想想
Let's see
我再也不用评卷了
I've got no more papers to grade
好
Yeah
其
In
其实  也没工作了
in fact, no more work
也没有课要上了
No more boating school classes
也不用开船了
No more driving
也没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
没有电话推销了
No more phone solicitors
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
没有公司团建百味餐了
No more company potlucks
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
没有路怒症了
No more road rage
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
没有保费了
No more insurance payments
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
裤头村监狱
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
我应该会喜欢上这里的
I think I'm going to like this place
没有泡芙老师的课堂不一样了
Class just isn't the same without Mrs. Puff
想想她的处境  在监狱里孤独受怕
Just the thought of her, alone and afraid in jail
让我想到她在监狱里孤独受怕
It makes me think about her
being alone and afraid in jail
我都不知道她得怎么安稳活下来
I don't know how she's going to survive
轻嗅美丽玫瑰
Smelling the pretty roses
幸福就像两种冰淇淋
Happiness is just two kinds of ice cream
可怜的泡芙老师
That poor woman
全都要怪我
And it's all my fault
也许去找派大星倾诉
Maybe if I go talk to Patrick
能让我不那么内疚
he can ease my guilt
听起来全都要怪你
Well, it sounds like it's all your fault
你说得对
You're right
泡芙老师坐牢了  全都要怪我
Mrs. Puff's in jail, and it's all because of me
我真是个缺心眼的
I'm such a barnacle-head
可怜的泡芙老师
Poor Mrs. Puff
有了
I know
我得救她出来
I got to get her out
不过要想让她出狱
But to get her out of jail
我们就得先进去
first we got to get in jail
要怎么进去
How we going to do that?
好  把钱放袋子里
All right, put the money in the bag
第一航海银行
放进来
Put it in
您方向反了  先生
You're facing the wrong way, sir
好
All right
把钱给我
give me the money
要从储蓄金里取钱
Will that be from your savings
还是从活期存款账户取钱
or your checking account, sir?
储蓄金
Savings
请出示身份证件
May I please see some identification?
好
Sure
给你看
There you go
谢谢
Thank you
捉水母俱乐部会员
海绵宝宝
先生  您两个账户余额
Sir, we are showing a balance
均为零元零角零分
of zero dollars and zero cents
for both of your accounts
下一位
Next
过程比预想的要顺利
That went better than expected
是啊  本来我还以为
Yeah, I didn't think
没法这么快就能把泡芙老师救出来
we'd get Mrs. Puff out of jail this fast
放心  派大星
Don't worry, Patrick
我们这次一定能进监狱
we'll get into jail this time
有对石头
There's a couple
加把劲  娘们
Put your back in it, girls
派大星你看  她在那
Look, Patrick, there she is
泡芙老师  等等
Mrs. Puff, wait
是我们
It's us
海绵宝宝和派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick
真奇怪
That's funny
我刚差点以为那颗黄石头跟我说话了
For a second, I thought that yellow rock talked to me
而且声音还很像
and its voice sounded a lot like
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
是我  海绵宝宝
It's me, SpongeBob
我们是要救你出来的
We're going to bust you out of here
快来  泡芙老师
Come on, Mrs. Puff
是你
It's you
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
为什么要跟着我进来
Why did you follow me in here?
为什么
Why?
好了  泡芙老师
All right, Mrs. Puff
看来你已经是中暑了
It looks like this heat's gone to your head
既然这么爱跟石头说话
If you're going to talk to rocks
那就去打饭
I guess it's time for you to go on kitchen duty
好
Yes
肯
It
肯定是我中暑了
it must be the heat
对
Yes
该死
Darn it
好了  派大星
Okay, Patrick
我们先走吧
let's get out of here
不  等下
No, wait
我们伪装服的押金付诸东流了
There goes our deposit on these costumes
厨房
去吃吧
There you are
泡芙阿姨好
Hey there, Puff Mama
今天吃什么
What's today's grub?
唐娜好
Hi, Donna
老样子  还是辣椒
It's chili, same as always
给你打一些吃
Let me get you some
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff
是我  海绵宝宝
it's me, SpongeBob
这些可怕的幻觉何时才会结束
When are these horrific hallucinations going to end?
不对  真的是我
No, it's really me
我也带派大星过来了
I brought Patrick along, too
嗨
Hi
为什么
Why?
因为我们要救你出来
Because we're going to set you free
不对  我是说
No, I mean
你为什么带他过来
why'd you bring him?
他喜欢辣椒
He likes chili
快点  趁没被看到赶紧进来
Now, quick, get in before someone sees
海绵宝宝  我不跟你走
SpongeBob, I am not going with you
真好笑  泡芙老师
That's a good one, Mrs. Puff
快点进来吧
Now hop in, come on
海绵宝宝  她好像是认真的
SpongeBob, I think she means it
太扯了  派大星
That's crazy, Patrick
他说得对  海绵宝宝
He's right, SpongeBob
我要留下来
I'm staying
为什么
But why?
我喜欢这里
I like it here
这些都是我的同类
These are my people
并且我坐牢
And besides, if I'm in here
就不用再应付你
that means I won't have to deal with you
你
you
理会自来水里的铀元素
Uranium in the water supply
看吧
See?
清澈见底
Crystal clear
先失陪一下  泡芙老师
Excuse us just one second, Mrs. Puff
派大星  她迷失了
Patrick, she has lost it
她彻底赖在这了
She's completely institutionalized
都忘了外面生活多逍遥
She's forgotten what it's like to live on the outside
远离牢笼多快活
To not be in prison
该睡觉了  老公
Coming to bed, honey?
好的  老婆
Yes, dear
得让她想起来还有比这更美好的生活
We've got to remind her there is life other than this
泡芙老师  跟我们走
Mrs. Puff, if you come with us
我就留校布置教室
I'll stay after school and decorate the whole classroom
再说最后一遍  不要
For the last time, no
我不跟你们走
I'm not going with you
最后通牒
That's final
又在跟没生命的物品说话了  泡芙
Talking to inanimate objects again, eh, Puff?
回你的牢房去
Get back to your cell
以后不安排你打饭
No more kitchen time for you
快  泡芙老师
Quick, Mrs. Puff
上来
hop on
狱警
Guards
快来
Come quick
我以前教过的发癫学生
There's a crazed ex-student of mine
跟他的胖朋友要来劫我出狱
and his overweight friend here to break me out
那只是做衣架的原材料
That's just raw material used to make coat hangers
你需要休息
You need some rest
快来  泡芙老师
Hop in, Mrs. Puff
狱警
Guards
过来看
Come look
我工资低  不负责帮你冲马桶
They don't pay me enough to do this job
泡芙老师  看上面
Mrs. Puff, up here
狱警
Guards
他们回来了
They're back
闹什么闹  泡芙
What's all the hubbub, Puff?
他们回来了
They're back
泡芙老师  是我们
Mrs. Puff, it's us
到底怎么一回事
What the barnacle is going on?
离我远一点
Get away from me
远点
Get away
你在胡言乱语什么  泡芙
What are you talking about, Puff?
你们骗不到我
You can't fool me
你们是海绵宝宝
You're SpongeBob
跟那个爱吃辣椒的
and that guy who likes the chili
认了吧  泡芙
Let's face it, Puff
你已经严重越界了
you've gone off the deep end
给我进去
Get in there, you
好好在单独禁闭室里反省一阵子
You need a nice long stay in solitary confinement
好吧
Oh, well
再往好的方面看
Let's look at the positives again
我终于能离那两个远远的了
I'm finally away from those two
对  自个儿待在我软绵绵的房间里
Yes, all alone in my nice soft room
海绵做的房间
Made of sponge
我能考过的  泡芙老师
I can pass the test, Mrs. Puff
我能考过的
I can pass the test
不许动
Freeze
兜风结束了  混账
Your joyride's over, punk
不要
No
什么
What?
不要啊
No, no
你们干什么
What are you doing?
救命
Help
不要
No
拜托
Please
我还有只蜗牛得喂
I have a snail to feed
警察
我还不能坐牢
I can't go to jail now
别现在就关我
This is not a good time
不要  拜托
No, please
我没有罪
please, I'm not a criminal
不敢相信
I can't believe it
原来只是场梦
It was all a dream
我不用去坐牢
I'm not going to jail
为什么要去坐牢
Why would you go to jail?
你已经坐牢了
You already did your time
原来又是我的想象
It's just my imagination again
今天晚上吃什么  泡芙阿姨
So what's for dinner tonight, Puff Mama
辣椒吗
chili?
算了吧
Forget it